<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ruby | Shiny happy people coding]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog-en.shingara.fr//blog/categories/ruby/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog-en.shingara.fr//"/>
  <updated>2012-07-12T09:35:23+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog-en.shingara.fr//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cyril Mougel]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[cyril.mougel@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dante lets you put some daemon in your code]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog-en.shingara.fr//dante-lets-you-put-some-daemon-in-your-code.html"/>
    <updated>2012-05-11T09:54:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog-en.shingara.fr//dante-lets-you-put-some-daemon-in-your-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Few days ago, I needed to convert a ruby script into daemon.</p>

<p>In my deployment toolkit, I use monitrc to monitor my scripts. Monit
checks a pidfile to know if the process is running or not.</p>

<p>So, I looked the best ruby solution to easily to transform this script in deamon
generating its own pidfile.</p>

<p>The most popular project in ruby to convert a ruby script into daemon is
<a href="http://daemons.rubyforge.org/">daemons</a>. I've tried several times in the past
and never became fan. It's too complicated and doesn't generate pidfile.
You have to manage everything yourself.</p>

<p>The second big project about managing daemon in the ruby community is
<a href="https://github.com/kennethkalmer/daemon-kit">daemon-kit</a>. I've tried it
several times without success. To me, it's way too big and not
flexible enough to use on a simple daemon script.</p>

<p>Therefore, I decided to see if the ruby community had a new
gem for this purpose. I discovered <a href="https://github.com/bazaarlabs/dante">dante</a>.
This project was exactly what I really needed. It really gets the job done.</p>

<p>By default, Dante manages few options in commandline. These options
are all what you really need. No more useless stuff.</p>

<p>Default options available :</p>

<p>```</p>

<pre><code>-p, --port PORT           Specify port
                          (default: )
-P, --pid FILE            save PID in FILE when using -d option.
                          (default: /var/run/scheduler.pid)
-d, --daemon              Daemonize mode
-l, --log FILE            Logfile for output
-k, --kill [PORT]         Kill specified running daemons - leave
</code></pre>

<p>blank to kill all.</p>

<pre><code>-u, --user USER           User to run as
-G, --group GROUP         Group to run as
-?, --help                Display this usage information.
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>You can define the PID, the log file, the user and group launching this
daemon (if launched in root). The only argument which is not essential to me is
the PORT. But this gem was created to launch rack applications. So
it's really needed in this case.</p>

<p>An other great feature is the option extension. You can add some new
options. Dante manage to you all options pass on your script.</p>

<p>To use it, it's really simple. You just put <code>Dante.run</code> and put your
code in a block. :</p>

<p><code>ruby
Dante.run('myapp') do |opts|
  myapp.run
end
</code></p>

<p>I am really impressed by this gem by the <a href="http://gomiso.com">gomiso</a>
company. Thanks for creating such a good gem.</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.shingara.fr/dante-pour-mettre-du-daemon-dans-son-code.html">Traduction Française</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moped the new mongoDB ruby driver]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog-en.shingara.fr//moped-the-new-mongodb-ruby-driver.html"/>
    <updated>2012-05-07T09:38:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog-en.shingara.fr//moped-the-new-mongodb-ruby-driver</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In December 2011, <a href="https://github.com/bernerdschaefer">Bernerd Schaefer</a> created a new MongoDB ruby driver.
This new driver is not supported by 10Gen (MongoDB creator) directly.
The official MongoDB ruby driver is the gem <a href="https://github.com/mongodb/mongo-ruby-driver">mongo-ruby-driver</a>.</p>

<h1>Goal of this gem</h1>

<p>This gem will be created after some frustration from the Mongoid Core
developer
The team proposed to change the internal software design on MongoDB Ruby driver but all changes were refused.</p>

<h2>Thread-safe</h2>

<p>One of this gem's goals was to have a more thread-safe gem than the official MongoDB ruby driver.
This official gem is sometimes considered like not 100% thread-safe like reported <a href="https://github.com/mperham/sidekiq/wiki/Problems-and-Troubleshooting">Mike Perham</a>.
Since the ruby community discovered again the thread, it hasn't stopped of being a real problem.
With Moped we can use <a href="http://mperham.github.com/sidekiq/">sidekiq</a>.</p>

<h2>No more extension</h2>

<p>If you want to use the MongoDB official driver, you will need to install another
gem <a href="http://rubygems.org/gems/bson_ext">bson_ext</a>.
Without it, you will have some performance penalties.
As this gem is a C extension, this gem has 2 versions in order to be compatible with JRuby.
One in C and the other in Java. It's therefore harder to maintain.</p>

<p>With Moped, no more extension needed.
Everything is done in pure ruby.
A benchmark shows that this moped's bson version is even faster than the C extension.</p>

<p>The only case where moped is slower than bson_ext is the ObjectId generation, like reported on <a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/mongoid/87IdIKO8-VM/discussion">Mongoid mailing-list</a>.
But, after all, Moped is new.
It can be improved in the future.</p>

<h2>Cleanest API</h2>

<p>The Moped API is really clean and simple.
It depends on the developers using it.
But, to me, it's a good API because it's really more "ruby way".</p>

<h2>Better Replicat Set management</h2>

<p>One of big feature of MongoDB is the ReplicatSet.
With Moped, the ReplicatSet management is even better.
There are no exception raise when a node is down.
The switch off of node is immediately done by Moped.</p>

<p>No need to list all of your node.
Moped does it automaticly with the MongoDB mechanism.
You can even add new nodes in your Replicat without restarting your application.</p>

<h1>Limitation</h1>

<p>Moped has some limitation in front of Mongo-ruby-driver.</p>

<h2>Ruby 1.9 only</h2>

<p>Moped works only with Ruby > 1.9. in order to avoid troubles with the 1.8 compatibilities.
For instance, the Socket on Ruby 1.8 series is not the best.</p>

<h2>No GridFS support</h2>

<p>GridFS is not supported on Moped.
This choice has been made to limit the size of the Moped code core.
In the future, this feature may be added in a Moped extension.</p>

<h1>Mongoid 3 integration</h1>

<p>Mongoid 3 now uses only MongoDB ruby driver.
Moped is a new dependency of Mongoid and mongo-ruby-driver is not anymore a dependencie.
If you want to try this new driver you can test it on Mongoid 3.</p>

<p>Warning: Mongoid 3 is still not released.
If you want to test it, you will need to use the Master branch on Mongoid.</p>

<p><code>ruby
gem 'mongoid', :git =&gt; 'git://github.com/mongoid/mongoid'
</code></p>

<p><a href="http://blog.shingara.fr/moped-le-nouveau-driver-mongodb-pour-ruby.html">French Translation</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
