<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gem | Shiny happy people coding]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog-en.shingara.fr//blog/categories/gem/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog-en.shingara.fr//"/>
  <updated>2013-09-11T18:27:14+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog-en.shingara.fr//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cyril Mougel]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[cyril.mougel@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dante lets you put some daemon in your code]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog-en.shingara.fr//dante-lets-you-put-some-daemon-in-your-code.html"/>
    <updated>2012-05-11T09:54:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog-en.shingara.fr//dante-lets-you-put-some-daemon-in-your-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Few days ago, I needed to convert a ruby script into daemon.</p>

<p>In my deployment toolkit, I use monitrc to monitor my scripts. Monit
checks a pidfile to know if the process is running or not.</p>

<p>So, I looked the best ruby solution to easily to transform this script in deamon
generating its own pidfile.</p>

<p>The most popular project in ruby to convert a ruby script into daemon is
<a href="http://daemons.rubyforge.org/">daemons</a>. I&rsquo;ve tried several times in the past
and never became fan. It&rsquo;s too complicated and doesn&rsquo;t generate pidfile.
You have to manage everything yourself.</p>

<p>The second big project about managing daemon in the ruby community is
<a href="https://github.com/kennethkalmer/daemon-kit">daemon-kit</a>. I&rsquo;ve tried it
several times without success. To me, it&rsquo;s way too big and not
flexible enough to use on a simple daemon script.</p>

<p>Therefore, I decided to see if the ruby community had a new
gem for this purpose. I discovered <a href="https://github.com/bazaarlabs/dante">dante</a>.
This project was exactly what I really needed. It really gets the job done.</p>

<p>By default, Dante manages few options in commandline. These options
are all what you really need. No more useless stuff.</p>

<p>Default options available :</p>

<p>```</p>

<pre><code>-p, --port PORT           Specify port
                          (default: )
-P, --pid FILE            save PID in FILE when using -d option.
                          (default: /var/run/scheduler.pid)
-d, --daemon              Daemonize mode
-l, --log FILE            Logfile for output
-k, --kill [PORT]         Kill specified running daemons - leave
</code></pre>

<p>blank to kill all.</p>

<pre><code>-u, --user USER           User to run as
-G, --group GROUP         Group to run as
-?, --help                Display this usage information.
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>You can define the PID, the log file, the user and group launching this
daemon (if launched in root). The only argument which is not essential to me is
the PORT. But this gem was created to launch rack applications. So
it&rsquo;s really needed in this case.</p>

<p>An other great feature is the option extension. You can add some new
options. Dante manage to you all options pass on your script.</p>

<p>To use it, it&rsquo;s really simple. You just put <code>Dante.run</code> and put your
code in a block. :</p>

<p><code>ruby
Dante.run('myapp') do |opts|
  myapp.run
end
</code></p>

<p>I am really impressed by this gem by the <a href="http://gomiso.com">gomiso</a>
company. Thanks for creating such a good gem.</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.shingara.fr/dante-pour-mettre-du-daemon-dans-son-code.html">Traduction Française</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quiet assets help you to have little log]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog-en.shingara.fr//quiet-assets-help-you-to-have-little-log.html"/>
    <updated>2012-04-26T09:39:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog-en.shingara.fr//quiet-assets-help-you-to-have-little-log</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One week ago, I discover a new gem really helpfull, <a href="https://github.com/evrone/quiet_assets">quiet_assets</a>.</p>

<p>This gem is not a big deal, but it help a lot when you develop a Rails
application ( > 3.1 ) with &lsquo;assets_pipeline&rsquo;. If you have a lot of
assets you have already see in your log a lot of information about
requests doing on this assets. You can see log like :</p>

<p><code>
Started GET "/assets/application.js?body=1" for 127.0.0.1 at 2012-02-13 13:24:04 +0400
Served asset /application.js - 304 Not Modified (8ms)
</code></p>

<p>After, when you want see the log really interresting about the request
you do, you need up on your log. It&rsquo;s really annoying. Our log file is
really bloat by this logs.</p>

<p>But <a href="https://github.com/evrone/quiet_assets">quiet_assets</a> is here to
help you in this mess. After adding this gem in your Gemfile.</p>

<p><code>
gem 'quiet_assets', :group =&gt; :development
</code></p>

<p>You can discover your log clean and light like before assets_pipeline. No more logs about your assets
request. Just your log you really need.</p>

<p>Some gem can really be usefull even if it&rsquo;s little.</p>

<p>Since rails 3.2.0, there are an option to define the logger of
Sprockets. All informations is on this <a href="https://github.com/rails/rails/issues/2639">issue 2639</a>.
But quiet_assets is allways usefull. When you define your sprocket&rsquo;s log to
false you have allways logs from actionpack. You have less log, but
allways too much.</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.shingara.fr/quiet-assets-le-limiteur-de-log.html">French Translation</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
